Guide to the Sidney Godolphin, Letterbook
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Letterbook]. Whitehall
1684-04-15-1684-08-19
OSBORN FB137
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.25
(1 volume)
Manuscript in an unidentified hand. The volume was used as a scrapbook in the 19th century, and most of the volume (170 f. in all) contains engravings, etc., cut from contemporary magazines and newspapers, and a few original drawings. Among the engravings is one after Bartolozzi, identified on the page opposite as the first attempt at engraving by William Chaughton (b. 1770), aged 17, late a ploughboy, and in 1787 a protege of Sir Joseph Banks, Bart. (1743-1820).
Total Volumes: 1
Godolphin, Sidney Godolphin, Earl of, 1645-1712
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb137. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Drawing, English; English wit and humor, Pictorial; Engravings, British; Romanticism in art -- Great Britain; Watercolor painting -- 19th century -- Great Britain; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1660-1688; Correspondence; Engravings (prints); Chaughton, William, b. 1770; Dolben, John, 1625-1686; Godolphin, Sidney Godolphin, Earl of, 1645-1712; Jenkins, Leoline, Sir, 1623-1685; Lindsey, Robert Bertie, Earl of, ca. 1630-1711; Mews, Peter, 1619-1706; Rutland, John Manners, Duke of, 1638-1711; Great Britain. Admiralty; Great Britain. Secretary of State
- OSBORN fb137
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Peter Mews, Bishop of Winchester (1619-1706)., 1684 Apr 15 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      Whitehall
      2 p.
      Resignation of Sir Leoline Jenkins
      (1623-85).
      f. 1
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Mr. Trennith., 1684 Apr 18 (Box 1)
      1 p.
      St. Ives charter and magistrates.
      f. 2
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - 5 ALS to John Dolben, Archbishop of York (1625-86)., 1684 Apr-May (Box 1)
      9 p.
      On appointment of Recorder of York.
      f. 2, 3, 4, 6, 7, 8
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to the bailiff and burgesses of Buckingham., 1684 Apr 29 (Box 1)
      Thomas Hillesdon to be re-elected
      bailiff.
      f. 3
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Ralph Stawell, 1st Baron Stawell (1641-89)., 1684 Apr 29 (Box 1)
      Steven Timwell, later mayor of
      Taunton, commended.
      f. 5
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Sir Thomas Chicheley (1613-89)., 1684 May 1 (Box 1)
      Summoned to appear before the King.
      f. 6
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Mayor of Newcastle-upon-Tyne., 1684 May 1 (Box 1)
      Samuel Fuller to be secured and sent
      to London.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Daniel Finch, 2nd Earl of Nottingham (1647-1730)., 1684 Aug 30 (Box 1)
      Apprehension of Captain Fuller.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to The Admiralty., 1684 May 12 (Box 1)
      Windsor
      Orders to seize a Spanish caper
      (privateer).
      Great Britain. Admiralty.
      f. 7
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to James Bertie, 1st Earl of Abingdon (1653-99)., 1684 Jun 12 (Box 1)
      On reappointment of Sir John
      Stonehouse, Bart. (1639-ca. 1700),
      as J.P.
      f. 8
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Richard Arundell, 1st Baron Arundell of Trerice (d. 1687)., 1684 Jun 17 (Box 1)
      Repair of Pendennis Castle postponed.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Sir Robert Sawyer (1633-92)., 1684 Jun 19 (Box 1)
      Unlicensed schoolmasters to be
      prosecuted.
      f. 9
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Mayor of Bristol., 1684 Jul 3 (Box 1)
      Abel Edwards to be discharged.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Sir Edward Hales (1645-95)., 1684 Jul 14 (Box 1)
      On appointment of Recorder and
      Deputy Recorder for Canterbury.
      f. 10
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Mayor of Southampton., 1684 Aug 12 (Box 1)
      New Charter for Southampton.
      f. 11
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to Robert Bertie, 16th Earl of Lindsey (ca. 1630-1711)., 1684 Aug 19 (Box 1)
      Duel with John Manners, 1st Duke of
      Rutland (1638-1711), forbidden.
      Duelling -- Great Britain.
      f. 11.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to William Craven, 1st Earl of Craven (1606-97)., 1684 Jul 17 (Box 1)
      On Justices of the Peace for St.
      Giles, Cripplegate.
  - GODOLPHIN, SIDNEY GODOLPHIN, 1ST EARL OF, 1645-1712.
    - Letter to William Dawson., 1684 Aug 14 (Box 1)
      Whitehall, 1 p.
      On new charter for Ripon.